# Ignacio Rafael Cisternas Núñez

#### Software & Mobile Developer

Software developer with 3 years of expertise in crafting solutions that meet client requirements. Committed to continuous improvement and delivering high-value work. Recognized for effective communication, dedication to quality, and strong teamwork skills, all contributing to successful project outcomes. Eager to embrace new challenges for ongoing personal and professional growth.

Principal Tech Stack: React Native, React, JavaScript, Typescript, Next.js, Jest, Node.js

#### **Experience**

#### Mobile Developer Consultant - Major Latin American Airline Holding — Thoughtworks. Santiago, Chile

05 / 2023 - Today

Front-end mobile developer and assistant technical leader for a loyalty program app tasked with delivering an MVP in production within 6 months using Micro Frontends architecture for the Brazilian market. As part of the enabling team, worked on both the app and parallel projects such as a design system utilizing Storybook and a core library enabling modules and services for all teams.

Achievements: Develop and deploy a multinational app with high quality standard and excellent ratings on stores.

Tech Stack: React Native, TypeScript, Jest

#### Mobile Developer Consultant - Major Latin American Retail Chain Store — Thoughtworks. Santiago, Chile

09 / 2022 - 05 / 2023

Part of a team challenged with developing a loyalty app within a 6-month timeframe. In his role as a Mobile Developer, he works on features such as digital wallet management, promotion deployment, notification systems, and personalized recommendations including testing.

Achievements: Creation from scratch of an app utilized by over 3 million people, successfully deployed with excellent ratings.

Tech Stack: React Native, TypeScript, Jest

#### Developer Consultant - National Infant Care and Nursery Company — Thoughtworks. Santiago, Chile

03 / 2022 - 07 / 2022

Participated in the initial Discovery phase, conducting interviews with professionals from Chile and Brazil to understand the problem to be addressed. Then contributed as a Full Stack developer on a platform utilizing Micro Frontends architecture for childcare management, incorporating BFF layers and connecting various backends to both relational and non-relational databases.

Achievements: Requirement gathering with child care professionals from Chile and Brazil. MVP delivery and successful pilot launch.

Tech Stack: React, TypeScript, Node.js, MySQL

### Front End Developer - Co-created APP dBarrio — dBarrio. Santiago, Chile

03 / 2020 - 01 / 2021

Involved as a Front End Developer within a self-managed team of 5 members, contributing to the creation of a B2B app that offers digital positioning to local stores through features like recommendation systems, georeferencing, and neighbor evaluations.

**Achievements:**- Best Academic Performance Award - FESW 2020. - Semifinalists in the INCmty Prototype Competition at Tecnológico de Monterrey 2020. - Interviews by digital media outlets and publications in newspapers.

Tech Stack: React Native, JavaScript

## Full Stack Developer Intern — Haulmer. Curicó, Chile

12 / 2019 - 02 / 2020

Worked with multiple teams to add new features, and refactor a B2B platform that handles invoices and payments for commerce.

Tech Stack: Angular, Ruby, PHP Laravel

## **Education, Certifications and Skills**

- Otras Tecnologías Python, Java, Go, C, Storybook, Docker, Git.
- Algunas Metodologías y Prácticas— Scrum, Kanban, TDD, DDD, Lean, Atomic Design.
- TOEIC B2 Level Certification, 910 Score 2020
- Universidad Técnica Federico Santa María Bachelor degree in Computer Engineering Graduated 2022